Welcome to this video. We will explore
today the capabilities of installing
preview versions of AppSource apps in
Business Central and see how you can
leverage this to test new versions of
your extension with your customers
before going live to a broader audience
in the AppSource marketplace.
We'll see
in this video how app publishers can
share preview versions of their app and
we'll also see how administrator can
install preview versions on sandbox
environments along with some good to
know about this.
As an AppSource publisher, when you're
setting up your offer in Partner Center,
you have the ability to specify a hide
key, which is the preview key that your
customers can use in order to access the
preview listing of your offer in the
marketplace, but also
to use the preview versions of your
extensions. So here the key for my offer
is defined to be maps and I can
introduce this into a well-defined
URL
and that contains also the tenant ID of
the customer I want to deploy this
extension for. Specify also the app ID
and the preview key
that I found in Partner Center.
Okay, after providing this URL to my
customers, they can use it on their
environment. This will trigger the usual
installation flow of extensions where
they can select which environments they
want the app to be installed and they
can now install this preview version on
their sandbox environment. A few things
that are good to know for AppSource
publishers.
We are currently only supporting to
install preview versions which are the
highest version of your extension. If
you have
public version that is higher, even if
you're giving a link with a preview key
to your customers, this
public version will be installed instead
on their environment.
You're sending the preview key as part
of the marketplace submission process as
we've seen previously, but if you do not
If you did not specify one, there is an
automatically generated preview key for
you. So, you're already opting in into
this feature without knowing it.
You can run simultaneous preview
versions for different offers with
different preview keys, even if those
different offers have the same apps.
Meaning, that you can have a very custom
behavior.
You will be allowed to perform breaking
changes between preview versions of your
extensions. If you're not satisfied with
the testing results and the behavior of
your app, you can do
changes without worrying about breaking
changes, as long as you are Do not
introduce breaking changes with the
latest public version.
Uh and when you're submitting a preview
version of your app, you should include
all the required dependencies as needed.
Otherwise, your submission partner
center might fail.
A few things that are good to know for
administrators.
Um previews can only be installed on
sandbox environments. You cannot install
them on production environments. This
also means that sandbox environments
with preview versions of an app
installed cannot be copied or restored
to a production.
Previews can be updated to higher
preview versions or public versions. So,
to install a newer
preview version, you would have to use
the install link including the preview
key. And to install a newer public
version, you can either use the link
without including the preview key, but
you can also update it directly from
admin center.
Installed preview versions are
automatically updated to higher public
version with app update guidance
setting. So, when your environment is
updated, your preview versions will be
updated
to newer version based on your
preferences.
Uh whenever an operation is done on
extensions, we're now logging into
telemetry whether the preview the app
application installed was in preview
versions or publicly available. So, you
can also trace
uh which type of apps you have on your
environment.
So, here are the links to some
additional resources for Business
Central. Thank you for watching this
video and please read the documentation
for additional details on this feature
and Business Central.